<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code and Random Hackery</title>
    <link>https://ruiwenchua.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Code and Random Hackery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 22:45:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ruiwenchua.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Single Repo for Statically Generated Sites on Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://ruiwenchua.com/2018/05/29/a-single-repo-for-statically-generated-sites-on-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 22:45:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruiwenchua.com/2018/05/29/a-single-repo-for-statically-generated-sites-on-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about how easy it is to setup a statically-generated blog (such as this!) using a static site generator and hosting it on Github pages.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at a simple git workflow that can be used to manage a statically-generated site, such as this.
Github pages usually publish the content from the master branch of a git repo, and while some tips found online might suggest keeping the generated content and the source material in separate repos, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to have them all in one project that can be managed all at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of a Kubernetes Cluster from the Outside with Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://ruiwenchua.com/2017/08/26/monitoring-of-a-kubernetes-cluster-from-the-outside-with-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruiwenchua.com/2017/08/26/monitoring-of-a-kubernetes-cluster-from-the-outside-with-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>When setting up a Kubernetes cluster, a Prometheus and Grafana setup is a great way to have to start monitoring your cluster health. From CPU and RAM stats, to filesystem usage, to even the number and type of requests that your cluster is serving. One thing however, is that most setups tend to assume that you&amp;rsquo;ll be deploying Prometheus within the cluster itself. To be sure, this is probably the easier way of settings things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes for small Organisations</title>
      <link>https://ruiwenchua.com/2016/10/30/kubernetes-for-small-organisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 23:30:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruiwenchua.com/2016/10/30/kubernetes-for-small-organisations/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes for small Organisations: Is it worth it?   I recently gave a talk at GeekcampSG 2016 about our ongoing experience with Kubernetes in Lomotif.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a technical deep-dive, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t talk very much about the implementation itself, but more about the experience in general, and the pitfalls that we came across. Hopefully, if you&amp;rsquo;re planning a move to Kubernetes, this talk could give you a heads up of a couple of gotchas that you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to pay attention to before jumping in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 16.04 on Raspberry Pi 3</title>
      <link>https://ruiwenchua.com/2016/10/03/ubuntu-16.04-on-raspberry-pi-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 01:30:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruiwenchua.com/2016/10/03/ubuntu-16.04-on-raspberry-pi-3/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to unify my dev environments, including my (very handy!) Raspberry Pi 3.
I&amp;rsquo;d gotten started with it with a Raspbian Jessie, but felt the new Ubuntu 16.04 was really more my speed. Thus began the journey to upgrade Pi OSes
Images First up, finding the right image. The good thing about the Pi community is that there&amp;rsquo;s so much activity, and so many community images. The bad thing is, well, that there are so many community images that it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes hard to tell which is going to work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>